Guide to the Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers TAM.544
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Richard Moser Collection on the GI Anti-Vietnam War Movement and Lordstown (Ohio) Automobile Workers
1970s-1990s
TAM.544
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
4.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
Richard Moser was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University until 1998, and the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996). About one half of the collection consists of oral histories on audiocassettes the majority pertaining to the GI anti-Vietnam War movement, with some pertaining to rank and file labor movement activity during the 1970s at the Lordstown, Ohio General Motors plant there, whose workers were represented by United Automobile Workers Local 112. There are also research notes, some correspondence, printed ephemera, and papers written by Moser's students.
Moser, Richard R., 1952-
Box 1-6
Historical/Biographical Note
Richard Moser earned his PhD from Rutgers University in 1992. Until 1998, he was an associate professor of American history at Middle Tennessee State University. He is the author of The New Winter Soldiers: GI and Veteran Dissent during the Vietnam Era (1996) and, with Van Gosse, is coeditor of The World the Sixties Made: Politics and Culture in Recent America (2003). He has also served as the National Organizer, American Association of University Professors.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by Richard Moser in 2010. The accession number 2010.054 is associated with this gift.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item’s original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that already have already been digitized are noted in the collection’s finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Contents note
About one half of the collection consists of oral histories on audiocassettes (there are also summaries and some transcripts), most pertaining to the GI anti-Vietnam War movement, with some pertaining to rank and file labor movement activity during the 1970s at the Lordstown, Ohio General Motors plant, whose workers were represented by the United Automobile Workers Local 112. Some interviews were conducted contemporaneously, others subsequently. There are also research notes, some correspondence, printed ephemera, and papers written by Moser's students.
Separated Materials
One box of GI anti-Vietnam War serials were separated to the Library's print collection, as was one box of books and pamphlets.
International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. Local 1112 (Lordstown, Ohio).; Moser, Richard R., 1952-; Audiocassettes.; Automobile industry workers |z Ohio |z Lordstown.; Interviews.; Lordstown (Ohio); Oral histories (document genres); Soldiers |z United States |x Political activity.; Videocassettes.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States.
- Lordstown Oral Histories (Box 1)
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories (Box 2)
  - Cline #1, Mar 1, 1988 (Box 2, Box Shared Access TAM Box 1)
  - Dave Kline #4, Mar 1, 1988 (Box 2, Box Shared Access TAM Box 1)
  - Dave Cline #3, Feb 15, 1988 (Box 2, Box Shared Access TAM Box 1)
  - Susan Schnall Part 1, Oct 25, 1990 (Box 2, Box Shared Access TAM Box 1)
  - Susan Schnall Part 2, Oct 25, 1990 (Box 2, Box Shared Access TAM Box 1)
- Vietnam GI movement Oral Histories (Box 3)
- Vietnam War Videocasettes: Documentaries (Box 4)
- The Invisible Force (Box 4)
- Only the Beginning (Box 4)
- "Veterans," film transfer Jun 27, 1991 (Box 4)
- Disobeying Orders: GI Resistance to the Vietnam War, Produce by Pam Sporn (Box 4)
- Vietnam GI Movement Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts) (Box 5)
- Lordstown Research Files (including interview summaries and transcripts) (Box 6)